Welcome to Essential Hayek
欢迎来到哈耶克简要
I'm Don Boudreaux
我是Don Boudreaux
professor of economics at George Mason University
乔治梅森大学经济学教授
senior fellow with the Fraser Institute
弗雷泽研究所高级研究员
and blogger at Café Hayek
博客Café Hayek的博主之一
This video was part of the Fraser Institute initiative
本视频是由弗雷泽研究所制作的
to present the key ideas of F.A. Hayek in an easily accessible format
对哈耶克关键思想的通俗介绍
In this video, we provide an overview of Hayek's life
这个视频是关于哈耶克的生平、
his accomplishments, and the events that influenced his thinking
成就和影响他思想的事件
Frederich A. Hayek was born in Vienna on May 8th, 1899
弗雷德里希A.哈耶克于1899/5/8出生于维也纳
As a young man, he served in the Austrian army during World War I
年轻时他加入了奥匈帝国陆军并参加了一战
Hayek soon found himself assigned to the Italian front
他被分配到了意大利前线服役
with his experience in combat had a profound and decisive influence on his life
这段战争经历给哈耶克的一生带来了深远且决定性的影响
Following the war, Hayek returned to Vienna
战争结束后，哈耶克返回了维也纳
and completed doctoral degrees in both law and political science
并获得了法律和政治学两个博士学位
Working as a young economist in Austria in the late 1920s
1920年代后期，哈耶克作为奥地利年轻的经济学家
Hayek was taken under the wing of noted economist Ludwig von Mises
在知名经济学家路德维希·冯·米塞斯的羽翼下成长
and began his work researching business cycles
并开始了对于经济周期的研究
Business cycles, or what were then called trade cycles
经济周期，后来亦叫商业周期
are known today as booms and recessions
今天被人们称作景气和衰退
In 1931, Hayek moved to England
1931年，哈耶克移居英国
and joined the faculty of the London School of Economics
于伦敦政治经济学院任教
With his research into booms and recessions
在1930年代大萧条的背景下
led to his growing fame, especially against the backdrop of the Great Depression of the 1930s
他对于经济周期的研究，使他声望日隆
During this time
在这期间
Hayek crossed path with his greatest intellectual rival
哈耶克遇上了他智力上最重要的对手
John Maynard Keynes
约翰·梅纳德·凯恩斯
who promoted the idea that governments could actively and successfully manage the economy
凯恩斯推广了政府可以积极、成功地调控经济的理念
Hayek argued in contrast
哈耶克则持相反观点
that an economy is too complicated
他认为经济太过复杂
and the information needed to make decisions too decentralized
决策所需的信息也太过分散
for a centrally planned economy to be efficient or effective
使得中央计划经济无法有效运转
Eventually, most economists and policymakers
最终，大多数经济学家和政治决策者
embraced Keynes' view of the world and the role of government
选择拥抱凯恩斯对于世界和政府角色的看法
which came to dominate economics thinking for the next forty years
这一潮流延续了四十年
Hayek was largely relegated to the sidelines
哈耶克则在很大程度上被主流经济学界遗忘了
But Hayek's time in the shadows was brief
不过哈耶克并未在阴影中待太久
In 1944
1944年
he published the classic volume,
他出版了经典之作——《通往奴役之路》
which became a bestseller
该书也成了畅销书
In 1950, Hayek moved to the University of Chicago
1950年，哈耶克前往芝加哥大学任教
where he published his second major work
在那他出版了他的第二部重要著作
《自由秩序原理》
Subsequent years would see the publication of two more big thick books
在之后的日子里他又出版了另外两本大部头
the three-volume
三卷本的《法律、立法与自由》
and, in 1988,
和1988年出版的《致命的自负》
In 1974, Hayek was awarded the Nobel prize in Economics
1974年，哈耶克被授予诺贝尔经济学奖
finally earning the professional acclaim that he’d lost with his refusal to jump onto Keynesian bandwagon
终于重获因当年与凯恩斯意见不同而失去的专业声誉
In 1991
1991年
the collapse of the Soviet Union provided further indication of Hayek's notion
苏联的解体为哈耶克关于
that central planning by government simply does not, indeed, cannot, work
政府中央计划经济无法、也不可能运转的见解提供了新的注脚
Readers interested in exploring Hayek's theories in greater depth
我们鼓励想更深入了解哈耶克理论的读者
are encouraged to read his works directly
直接阅读哈耶克的著作
I recommend starting with
我建议从《通往奴役之路》开始
and economic students might wish to start with Hayek's influential 1945 essay
经济系学生可能会希望从哈耶克1945年那篇极富影响力的文章
《知识在社会中的运用》开始
To learn more and to download  for free
想要了解更多或者下载《哈耶克简要》
visit www.essentialhayek.org
请访问www.essentialhayek.org
翻译 by tcya